# Katie Caulfield

703-728-2302 | caulfieldke@gmail.com | LinkedIn | Portfolio

## PROFESSIONAL PROFILE

Learning and development professional with over 7 years of experience creating engaging and enriching content for the high school science classroom. Developed curriculum for high school Chemistry and met the needs of over 1,100 learners using diverse methodologies of instruction. Took the traditional classroom experience and quickly learned new digital tools effectively to ensure learners received the same quality education through both synchronous and asynchronous virtual instruction during the COVID-19 pandemic.

### **EXPERIENCE**

#### **Professional Development Presenter**

August 2022

Selected as 1 of 8 instructional leaders among a staff of 208 members to develop and present, to a group of fellow educators, a meaningful training experience to enrich their own instruction with students.

- Worked in a team of 3 to compose a training program focused on self-regulated learning.
- Delivered training on the phases of self-regulated learning to a group of over 30 adult learners using an interactive slide deck.

#### **Chemistry Cohort Leader**

November 2021 – Present

Facilitated meetings for team of 4 Chemistry teachers to discuss Chemistry content, pedagogy, and assessment.

- Engineered learning opportunities that highlighted essential research skills needed by science students.
- Coordinated the implementation of these learning opportunities with other Chemistry teachers to improve positive student impact.
- Aligned multiple teachers' weekly lesson plans to distribute scarce lab resources equitably and ensure all students had the opportunity to use school-funded lab supplies.
- Mentored new Chemistry teachers as they charted their way through the Virginia Department of Education's curriculum.
- Helped devise solutions for flexibility of instruction to ensure all team members could meet the goals set by both the Chemistry team and supervisors for a diverse set of learners.

#### **Educator (Chemistry and Biology)**

August 2015 – Present

Responsible for teaching and shaping the academic, social, and personal development of students in grades 9-12.

- Pioneered novel approach to teaching high school Chemistry by utilizing digital tools like Edpuzzle to establish a flipped classroom.
- Maintained high pass rate of 99% for the designed course.
- Analyzed quantitative data from learning management systems to drive instruction based on formative student feedback.
- Tracked progress to meet personal initiatives with an average of 85% of learners meeting or exceeding the set goals.

#### **Science Practices Innovation Notebook Collaborator**

June 2019 - June 2022

Identified as 1 of 19 leaders in science curriculum throughout all countywide staff of 588 secondary science educators and asked to design curriculum to be showcased in a new interactive science notebook.

- Collaborated with other educators and subject matter experts to construct a new interactive science notebook to be incorporated into Google G Suite.
- Designed lessons to be used nationally through the online interactive notebook.
- Iterated on these lessons to refine them prior to testing the functionality of the beta-version of the program.

• Worked in cross-functional team to identify the needs of users, both instructors and learners, to design instructional materials and tools necessary to use program effectively.

# **EDUCATION/CERTIFICATIONS**

Adobe Education June 2022

**Level 1 Creative Educator** 

**Level 2 Creative Educator** 

Completed a critical thinking and creativity course called Creativity for All as well as a course called Design your Creative Class or Course hosted by Adobe Education

Virginia Department of Education

Renewed Until June 30, 2032

# **Collegiate Professional License**

- Biology
- Chemistry

College of William and Mary

**Bachelor of Science in Biology** 

# PROFESSIONAL LEARNING

LinkedIn Learning January 2023 – February 2023

**E-Learning Essentials: Storyboarding** 

Learned the benefits of storyboarding, storyboard elements, and creating storyboards with text, animation, scenarios, and knowledge checks

#### **E-Learning Essentials: Instructional Design**

Reviewed features of a learning management system (LMS), backwards design, and accessibility in design

Skillcrush September 2022

**Coding Camp** 

Learned about the foundational concepts of HTML 5, CSS 3, JavaScript, User Experience, and Visual Design

# **SKILLS**

Microsoft Office SuiteHTML 5FigJamGoogle G SuiteCSS 3FigmaAdobe Creative Cloud ExpressJavaScriptWeVideoVisual Studio CodeCanvaKahoot